Resume:

Personal data

- Diego Fernando Luisi
 - o Brazilian, Married
 - Rua Guilherme Gomes Fernandes, 5A Amadora/Lisbon Portugal
 - o Date of Birth: 12/02/1986
 - +351 910910296
 - o **4** LPI000249557
 - o 🐸 contato@diegoluisi.eti.br
 - o 🌐 https://www.diegoluisi.eti.br
 - o in LinkedIn
 - ∘ Ω GitHub

Summary of qualifications

• Enthusiastic about the DevOps culture and passionate about Open Source, I have 20 years of background as a SysAdmin, currently working as an SRE, open to learning new technologies and procedures to improve every day more as a professional.

Professional Expectations

Provide resilient solutions in an agile way, which make it possible to optimize processes, have
efficient operations, reduce costs, allow rapid expansion and present new options that add value and
make them more competitive.

Academic education

- Nove de Julho University (Uninove)
 - Technology in Computer Networks
 - o Sao Paulo-SP
 - o Period: 2017
- University of West Paulista (Unoeste)
 - Information systems
 - President Prudente SP
 - o Period: 2004 to 2007 (incomplete)

Languages

• English

- o Read / Write Advanced
- Conversation Advanced
- Spanish
 - o Reading / Writing Basic
 - o Conversation intermediate

Certificates and Badges

- Istio Expert
- Istio Essentials
- Istio Foundation
- GitOps Fundamentals
- Scrum Fundamentals Certified
- SonicWALL Network Security Basic Administration (CSSA)
- SonicWALL Network Security Advanced Administration (CSSP)
- ITIL® v3 Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

Trainings and Workshops

- [solo.io] Operationalizing Istio [Expert]
- [solo.io] Deploy Istio for Production [Essentials]
- [solo.io] Get Started with Istio [Foundation]
- [codefresh] GitOps Fundamentals
- [AWS] Developing on AWS (AWS SDK, IAM, S3, DynamoDB, SNS, SQS, Lambda, Cognito)
- [DO180] Introduction to Containers, Kubernetes, and Red Hat OpenShift
- [526] DevOps Master (24 hours)
- [4435] JBoss AS 7 Administration with High Performance and Productivity
- [525] Agile infrastructure with Devops practices (Ansible, AWS, Docker, GitLab, Jenkins, Puppet and Rundeck)
- [SUSE-SOC201] OpenStack Administration with SUSE (40 Hours)
- [AIX-AN30] Power Systems for AIX PowerVM (40 Hours)
- [SMGR210] SuSE Manager 3 Administration (24 Hours)
- [CNS-220] Citrix Netscaler Essential CNS-220 (24 Hours)
- Puppet Fundamentals (24 Hours)
- Puppet Practitioner (24 Hours)
- Puppet Introduction (8 Hours)
- [AIX-AN140BR] AIX Jump Start (40 Hours)
- [SUSE3126] SuSE Linux Enterprise server 12 (40 Hours)
- SonicWALL Network Security Basic Administrator (40 hours)
- VMware Implementing and Managing ESXi and vCenter 5.1 servers (20 hours)
- [LX0-101/102] Linux Preparatory course LX0-101/102 (8 weeks)
- ITIL V3 Foundation (18 hours)
- Zimbra Collaboration Suite (4 hours)
- Zabbix Enterprise Open Source Monitoring Solution (4 hours)
- NGINX High Performance Web Servers (3 hours)
- Mysql Database Management (3 hours)

Professional Experiences

Evolution

- Position: SRE (Site Reliability Engineering).
- Lisbon, Lisbon Portugal 🗖
- 04/2022 current
- Follow-up: Gaming
- Role:
 - As an SRE, my challenge is to work with the development and product teams and create automations that provide better observability of the application, guaranteed by automated processes that facilitate the deployment of new applications, generating greater competitiveness for the business.
- Technologies:
 - [ArgoCD, Crossplane, GCP, GKE, GitHub, GitHub Actions, Helm, Istio, Kubernetes, Loki, OpenShift, SealedSecrets]

Dafiti Group (GFG Group)

- Position: SRE (Site Reliability Engineering).
- São Paulo, SP Brazil 🜌
- 09/2020 04/2022
- Follow-up: e-commerce
- Role:
 - Technical leader of Squad DevXP, my role is to bring the best development practices and ensure a better development experience and ensure that reliable code will be delivered in production, in an automated and safe way.
- Technologies:
 - [AlertManager, ASG, ArgoCD, Backstage, Circle-Cl, CodeDepoy, Crossplane, Docker, EC2, EKS, Grafana, Graylog, GitHub, Helm, Istio, Kiali, Lambda, NGINX, Prometheus, Puppet, R53, RabbitMQ, Redis, S3, SealedSecrets, Terraform, Terragrunt, Vault]

C&A Modas do Brasil

- Position: DevOps Specialist.
- Function: Application modernization, pipeline creation and process automation.
- Barueri, SP Brazil 🜌
- 08/2019 09/2020
- Follow-up: Retail
- Role:
 - Responsible for the modernization of applications and infrastructure, I had the challenge of transforming legacy applications into micro services by adopting practices of containerization and automation of processes and pipelines and cloud services.
- Technologies:
 - [Docker, ELK, Elasticsearch, Filebeat, GitLab, Gitlab-Cl, Grafana, Icinga2, Kafka, Kibana,
 Logstash, OpenShift, Prometheus, Puppet, Puppet-Bolt, R10k, Satellite, Terraform, Vagrant]

Dafiti Group (GFG Group)

- Position: Senior/Specialist DevOps Engineer.
- Function: Application modernization, pipeline creation and process automation.
- São Paulo, SP Brazil 🜌
- 10/2017 08/2019
- Follow-up: e-commerce
- Technologies:
 - [AWS, CloudWatch, ELK, Filebeat, Git, Grafana, InfluxDB, Kibana, Kubernetes, Memcached,
 Metricbeat, NGINX, Puppet, Puppet-Bolt, R10k, Redis, Rundeck, Terraform, Vagrant, Zabbix]

C&A Modas do Brasil

- Position: Senior SysAdmin.
- Barueri, SP Brazil 🜌
- 08/2014 10/2017
- Follow-up: Retail
- Technologies:
 - [AIX, Centrify, Device42, GitLab, GitLabCI, JAVA, Jenkins, MCollective, MacOS Server,
 Netscaler, OpenScap, Oracle, PowerVM, Puppet, Puppet-DB, Puppet-Explorer, Rundeck, SALT,
 SuSE Linux, SuSE-Manager, VMware, X-Store, r10k]

e-Deploy Integrated Technology and Solutions

- Position: Senior SysAdmin/Monitoring
- Barueri, SP Brazil 🔯
- 08/2013 07/2014
- Follow-up: Technology
- Technologies:
 - [Linux, RedHat, Zabbix, Grafana, MySQL, Sonicwall, JBoss, VMWare]

Grupo Logos – Logistics and Planned Transport

- Position: Senior SysAdmin
- Barueri, SP Brazil 🜌
- 01/2012 09/2013
- Follow-up: Logistics and Transport
- Technologies:
 - [Active Directory, Bind9, Fail2Ban, Grafana, GitLab, GitLab CI, MCollective, Postgrey, Puppet, Puppet-Board, Sonicwal, VMware, Xeams, Zabbix, Zimbra]

FETAESP - Federation of Agricultural Workers of the State of São Paulo

- Position: SysAdmin
- Agudos, SP Brazil 🔯
- Duration: 04/2010 to 03/2011
- Follow-up: Union Body.
- · Technologies:
 - [Active Directory, Hyper-v, Terminal Service, Sarg, Squid, Squid-Guard, ThinStation, XP Unlimited]

Santa Alice Group

- Position: SysAdmin
- Presidente Prudente, SP Brazil 🔯
- Duration: 05/2006 to 09/2008
- Follow-up: Secondary and elementary education institution.
- · Technologies:
 - [Active Directory, Iptables, Squid, Squid-Guard, Sarg]

e-Future Informatics

- · Position: Owner
- Presidente Prudente, SP Brazil 🔯
- Duration: 04/2002 to 09/2008
- Follow-up: IT Maintenance and Support Company.
- Functions Performed:
 - Support, Design, Installation and Maintenance on Servers and Network.

Specific knowledge

Operation System

Linux/Unix (Red Hat, SuSE, Debian, CoreOS, HP-UX and IBM-AIX)

Microsoft

- Windows Server/Hyper-V (2000, 2003, 2008, 2012)
 - [AD, DFS, DNS, DHCP, FTP, GPO, IIS, TS, WSUS]

Tooling

- APM:
 - o New Relic and Instana.
- AntiSpam:
 - o Xeams, Sophos, SpamAssassin.
- Cache:
 - Redis, MemCached.
- CI/CD:
 - o ArgoCD, Bamboo, CircleCl, CodeDeploy, GitLab Cl, GitHub Actions, Jenkins and Travis.
- Configuration Management:
 - Ansible, Chef, Puppet, PuppetDB, Puppet-Explorer, MCollective, Puppet Bolt, Terraform and Salt.
- Containers:
 - o Docker, OpenShift, EKS, Kubernetes, Rancher.
- Data base:
 - Mysql, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, MongoDB and Oracle.
- DNS Server:
 - o Bind9.
- File Server:

- SAMBA.
- ITSM / CMDB:
 - Jira/Confluence, Device42, GLPI, Ocs Inventory and OTRS.
- Log Management:
 - o Graylog, ELK.
- Mail Server:
 - o Zimbra, Postfix, Dovecot.
- Middleware:
 - o Apache, JBoss, Nginx, Tomcat, Weblogic.
- Monitoring:
 - Prometheus, Nagios, Oracle Enterprise Manager (OEM12) and Zabbix.
- Open Source System Management:
 - o Spacewalk, SuSE-Manager, Satellite.
- Proxy Server:
 - o Squid, Sarg, SquidGuard.
- Version Control System (VCS):
 - o BitBucket, Gitlab and Github.
- VoIP Server:
 - o Asterix, Elastix.

Cloud

- · OpenStack.
- Amazon Web Services (AWS):
 - [ACM, ALB, ASG, Athena, Cloud Formation, Cloud Front, Code Deploy, DynamoDB, EBS, ECR, ECS, EC2, EKS, ElastiCache, ELB, GLACIER, IAM, KMS, LAMBDA, RDS, R53, SNS, SQS, S3, VPC]
- Google Cloud Platform (GCP):
 - [VPC, GKE]

The Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF)

- Kubernetes
 - Application Definition & Image Build
 - Backstage, Kustomize, Helm, DevSpace and Okteto
 - Secret Management
 - Cert Manager, Bitnami Sealed Secrets, Hashicorp Vault
 - Continuous Integration & Delivery:
 - ArgoCD AutoPilot, ArgoCD, Argo Events, Argo Workflows and Argo Rollouts
 - Logging and Tracing
 - Kiali, Jaeger, ELK, FluentBit and Promtail
 - Monitoring
 - Alert Manager, Prometheus, Grafana and Loki
 - Network Policies
 - Calico
 - Scheduling & Orchestration
 - Crossplane

- Service Mesh
 - Istio

Virtualization

- Hyper-V
- IBM PoweVM
- KVM
- ProxMox
- VMWare

Unified Threat Management (UTM)

- Cisco
- Juniper
- Netscaler
- Sonicwall (CSSA and CSSP)

Data Storage

- HP 3Pair
- IBM V7000

Methodologies/Frameworks

- Agile
- ITIL
- Kanban
- Scrum